On a mountaintop in the dead of winter,
a group of faithful men
gathered an audience
to share their vision.
They had seen a gleaming city
bathed in golden light.
The city would be filled with buildings
so beautiful they would seem
to float above the earth
as if descended from heaven.
Their vision already had a name...
[Kushner]
So, let's see if these things work.
They never usually work.
The mountaintop in question
was the resort town of Davos.
The faithful men presenting their vision
were U.S. real estate moguls
Jared Kushner and Steve Witkoff.
Well, this is a very exciting day.
See, I'm a real estate person at heart,
and it's all about location.
Look at this beautiful piece of property.
[Kushner]
Let's just plan for catastrophic success.
Out of the horrors
of a live-streamed Genocide,
an exclusive paradise was
about to emerge fully formed.
[Kushner]
We've already started removing the rubble,
and doing some of the demolition.
We've heard this story
of golden cities before.
[Reagan]
I've thought a bit of the 'shining city upon a hill.'
Some versions of it
are told and retold
in the sacred texts of Judaism,
Christianity and Islam.
[Hagee]
In God's Prophetic Clock:
The Seven Signs for the End of Days—
First the horror,
—Then we come to the place of Armageddon.
The mass death.
—This is going to be your payday
for the next 50 million years.
A battle of Armageddon—
Then for the blessed survivors,
a new Jerusalem,
but only for the favored few.
—Hallelujah!
The apocalyptic prophecies
are just a prediction
of what humans are likely to do.
Today's far right is united,
I mean, civilization could
die with a bang or a whimper.
—by their belief in variations
of this age old apocalyptic myth.
What I'm trying to focus on
is doing as much of God's work
as possible right now.
And if that leads to the end times,
okay.
This is the dark core of the rising threat
and ideology that we call...
—like having a company that thrives in bad times.
You know, bad times
are very good for Palantir.
An ominous evolution is underway
on the internationally networked hard right.
The future of civilization
could hang on this election.
[Robinson]
We weathered the storm,
and today we are the storm.
[Musk]
Whether you choose violence or not,
violence is coming to you.
You either fight back,
or you die.
A shift related to the reality
that humanity has entered
an era of global scale
existential crisis.
A world where pandemics,
climate emergencies,
resource wars
and rogue tech are routine,
and where politics stirs the pot.
A world where the
growing masses of unruly poor
must be constantly tracked and contained.
[MrBeast]
Welcome to Billionaire Bunker.
This is crazy!
And where the fortunate few.
This $50 million bunker is designed
to look like you're not in a bunker.
Pay top dollar
for both protection,
and escape.
This will be a victory for real people.
After the UK voted
to leave the European Union,
triggering an economic crisis,
Jeffrey Epstein sent
a celebratory note to Peter Thiel,
the billionaire venture capitalist.
Trump's former chief strategist Steve Bannon
reached out to Epstein soon after.
Eager to find ways to turn that tribalism
into a global,
far right counterrevolution.
Across the globe,
different countries
have served as testing grounds
for different parts
of this emergent agenda.
Each one,
feeding,
on collapse.
[Miller]
You can talk all you want
about international niceties
and everything else.
But we live in a world,
in the real world, Jake,
that is governed by...
strength,
that is governed by force,
that is governed by power.
Fascism always emerges
in moments of systemic crisis.
It combines state power
with popular passions
to protect the elites from the threats
of redistribution and accountability.
It accomplishes this by
directing mass anger and frustrations downward,
away from the politicians
and oligarchs at the top,
toward vulnerable scapegoats.
And always in the crosshairs...
There is now a resurgence
of the communist menace in our land.
The left.
[Rubio]
This is what radical leftism is.
It is a poisonous resentment
cloaked in the language of equality
and justice and liberation,
to wreck what is beautiful
and what is right.
But our point is not simply to say
it's happening again.
Today's fascism doesn't look
like the ordered an industrial past.
It looks like the frenetic,
always online,
never stop monetizing,
bot infested present.
No, today's fascists
are not more dangerous than last century's.
Number one, we are close to creating a genie
that can grant any wish.
But our world,
is more dangerous than their world.
Its weapons deadlier,
its technologies vastly more potent,
its media more concentrated,
Thank you, Mr. President.
We certainly couldn't
do this without you.
—and its climate more unstable.
[Announcer]
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome
the president of the United States,
Donald J. Trump.
If we're waiting for soldiers
goose stepping in formation.
[Announcer]
Special thanks to our sponsor, Palantir.
We'll miss the
messianic venture capitalists,
[Hegseth]
You can do better [unintelligable yelling]
—the army controlling theocratics,
and the grifting manosphere influencers.
End times fascism is not a monolith.
It's a dangerous and fractious alliance,
of three main groups.
From the very beginning, it's been clear
that God has a special plan
and purpose for the nation of Israel.
You know, I think AI will probably
like most likely
sort of lead to the end of the world.
But in the meantime,
there will be great companies created.
America is fighting
with Israel for a common goal,
to protect our future,
to protect civilization
against these barbarians.
That's a good take right there.
Sieg fucking heil!
Let's fucking go!
You would prefer
the human race to endure, right?
Uh...
You're hesitating.
Yeah, well, I...
End times fascists haven't
just given up on liberal democracy.
They've given up on the possibility
of a shared future for all of us.
The most powerful people in the world,
—are preparing for the end of the world.
An end they themselves are both accelerating,
—and profiting from.
Whether in their luxury bunkers,
locked behind fortress borders,
or escaping Earth altogether.
—their souls raptured to heaven,
their minds uploaded to the AI cloud,
Their bodies hurtling
in rockets to the stars.
[Movie Narrator]
They lived only to face a new nightmare:
the war against the machines.
We have imagined Armageddon
so many times,
it can almost feel inevitable.
Except it's not.
So, which side are you on?
The side of bunkering down,
abandoning Earth
and profiting from apocalypse.
Or staying loyal
to this planet and its people.
[Activist]
Who are you aligned with?
Who are you protecting?
And making life here better.